Let's review.
我们复习一下
So far we've learned that a linear layout can have an orientation that's
目前我们学习了线性布局的方向属性
horizontal or vertical.
分别是水平 竖直
But now let's think about whether these views are taking full advantage of
但我们可以思考的是这些视图是否充分利用了
the screen real estate.
屏幕的实际空间
When I say real estate, I mean the available space on the screen.
我所说的 real estate 意思是屏幕中的可用空间
For our Nexus 6 phone,
对于我的 Nexus 6 手机
say we have a vertical linear layout that has three child text views inside.
假设是垂直线性布局 里面有三个 TextView
Tom, Tim and Todd.
Tom、Tim 和 Todd
When we hold the device in portrait mode like this in our hand,
当我们的设备是竖向模式 就像这个一样
then all the text views are grouped in the top left corner of the screen.
所有的 TextView 集中在屏幕左上角
There's all this blank space left unused.
这些空白的空间都没被使用
Similarly, if we rotated the device to Landscape mode,
类似 如果旋转设备到横向模式
then the text is on the top left corner and there's all this blank space left.
文字在左上角 这边是剩下没使用的空间
It's even more noticeable on a tablet device,
在平板设备上更显而易见
where the screen is a lot bigger.
因为屏幕更大
We're only using a small amount of the screen real estate, and
我们只使用可用空间的一小部分
the rest of it is blank.
剩下的都是空着的
We're going to learn about how we can more equally spread out these views
接下来我们要学习如何将这些视图铺开
across the screen to take up more of the available room.
在整个屏幕上占据更多空间
This applies to other views as well.
这同样适用于其它设备
You can have bigger images across the screen for
你可以使用大一点的图片布满屏幕
a better experience, instead of having them really tiny in the top left corner.
来获得更好的视觉体验 而不是在左上角的那么小
Same with buttons,
按钮也一样
you could have bigger buttons so that it's easier To tap on those buttons.
你可以设置大按钮 这样方便你点击
For the purposes of our example, we're going to stick with text views.
出于这样的目的 我们将继续学习 TextView
So let's go to the XML visualizer to figure out how we can spread out
那让我们去 XML 可视化工具学习如何扩展
these views.
这些视图
So here's the code for Tom, Tim, and Todd.
这是Tom、Tim 和 Todd 的代码
I have three text views within a vertical linear layout and
现在三个 TextView 是垂直布局的
this is what they look like on the device.
这就是它们在设备上的样子
Now, I want to show you how you can spread out these three text views.
现在我想告诉你如何扩展这三个 TextView
So that Tom is up here.
Tom 在最上面
Tim is here.
Tim 在这
And Todd is down here.
Todd 在最下面
Clearly, setting height for wrap_content is not doing the job.
很明显 设置高度为 wrap_content 的并不起作用
The other thing we learned is to set a fixed dp value for the height.
我们还要学习将高度设置为一个固定的dp值
So I'm going to set the height to be, for example, 200dp.
例如 我把高度设置为 200dp
Cool. So that left a lot more space for Tom.
这样就给Tom 留下了更多的空间
If I do the same for the other TextViews,
如果我对其它 TextView 做同样操作
then they also spread out more evenly across the screen.
它们就会扩展很多 甚至充分利用整个屏幕
But this solution will only work for the sides of a device.
但是这种方法只对这个设备起作用
If I have a tablet like I showed you earlier, then these views are still
如果换成平板电脑 这些视图就还是会保持原样
going to be grouped in somewhat of the top left corner.
聚集在左上角
The other option for setting height is match parent which we learned earlier.
设置高度的另一个选择就是之前学到的 match_parent
When you set match parent for the Tom TextView
当你对 Tom 的 Text View 设置 match_parent
it takes the height of the whole parent which is a whole screen.
这时候高度跟整个屏幕一样
That pushes the other text views off the screen so you can't even see them.
这就使其它 TextView 被挤出屏幕 看不到了
So let's not do that.
最好不要这样
Well now we're out of ideas because we tried wrap content for
现在好像没办法了 因为我们已经尝试了 wrap_content
the height, which had a fixed DP value.
这时的高度是固定值
And we tried match parent.
也尝试了match_parent
And none of those give us the right spacing across all different devices.
这些方法并没有解决在所有设备上显示的问题
Let's Google search for a potential solution to this problem.
在 Google 上搜索一下这个问题的解决方法
We're using a linear layout view group.
我们正使用 LinearLayout 的 ViewGroup
And we want to equally space out the children views.
想得到等分空间的子视图
So let's search for that.
让我们找找看
Okay, so there's a bunch of search results, but
这有一堆搜索答案
let's click on this first one.
我们选第一个
This is a link to the Stackoverflow site.
这是 Stack overflow 网站的链接
It's a Q&amp;A site where you can post questions and
在网站的问答板块你可以提问
get answers from other Android developers.
获得其他 Android 开发者的回答
I use it all the time when I'm stuck and I need help on a problem.
我遇到问题需要帮助时经常用它
Often times other people will have already asked a question
一般情况下是已经有人问过和我
that I'm having.
同样的问题了
So this question here is about how to evenly distribute buttons
这个问题问的是如何在 LinearLayout 水平方向上
across the width of a linear layout.
均等的分布按钮
This is similar to what we're looking for,
这和我们要找的类似
except instead of buttons we're working with text views.
除了提问中针对是按钮而我们的是TextView
And instead of the width of the linear layout we're trying to spread it across
还有就是在Linear Layout中均分宽度 而我们是想扩展
the height of the linear layout.
LinearLayout 的高度
We can read through the question or we can skim it.
我们可以仔细阅读也可以略读
Usually I just skim for the answer.
通常我只是略读这些问题
So this solution received 88 votes and has a green checkmark on it.
这个方法有88个赞而且已经被采纳
It talks about how you can set layout_width to 0dp and
这个是说如何设置 layout_width 为 0dp
set the layout_weight for each of the buttons to be 1.
每个按钮的 layout_weight 为1
And that splits the available width equally across the buttons.
这条问题可用 都是均分按钮空间
You may not fully understand the answer at this point, but that's okay.
也许现在你不是很明白 没关系
One key phrase that we saw is this linear layout_weight.
关键短语是 linear layout_weight
We haven't encountered this before, but it sounds important to the answer.
之前我们没听过 不过对这个问题很重要
So lets copy it and Google search for
复制然后在 Google 搜索
more information Information about layout_weight.
更多有关 layout_weight 的信息
So let's search for linear layout layout_weight.
搜索 linear layout layout_weight
The first result is an article for linear layout and
第一条结果是 Linear Layout 的一篇文章
it's on the developer.android.com site, so let's click on it.
是在 developer.android.com 这个网站上的 点进去
So this is an article about the Linear Layout.
这是有 关Linear Layout 的文章
We already learned the stuff at the top about the Android orientation attribute,
我们之前已经学了大量有关 Android 方向属性的知识
but then there's new information about something called Layout Weight.
现在又出现了新的知识 Layout Weight（布局权重）
There's also an example at the bottom of the screen here with some code and
屏幕下方还有一个例子 有代码
a screenshot.
和屏幕截图
I could summarize all of this for
我可以概括的告诉你
you, but first I want to give you a chance to read this document.
但是我想让你自己读一下这些文件
And try to figure it out on your own.
尝试自己解决这个问题
This is going to be a lot more similar to how you're going to solve problems
这和你以后自己解决问题一样
after this course is over.
学习完课程之后
You'll look for some information online and
你将在网上寻求信息
try to figure out how that can be used to solve your problem.
尝试怎样才能解决问题
Okay, so this is the layout that we have now on the device.
这是现在设备上的布局
And this is what we want to achieve.
这个是我们想达到的最终效果
The three texts are spread-out evenly across the height of the device.
三个控件在设备竖直高度上平均分布
To solve this problem,
为了解决这个问题
I want you to read the Linear Layout article that we linked below.
我需要你阅读后面链接的文章
It's perfectly normal for
那将非常完美
you to not understand everything that's in the article.
如果你能明白全文
Often times you just want to have some vague understanding
很多时候你只是大概理解
of how the concepts in the article may be able to help you in your work.
文章中的概念是怎样帮你解决问题
Then I want you to provide some ideas on how we can build this desired
我希望你能提供几种解决办法
layout in XML.
关于在 XML 中构建想要的布局
You don't need to provide the full XML layout code
你不需要提供整个 XML layout 的代码
because we're going to walk through that together in the next video.
因为在下一个视频中我们将一起继续学习
But here you could write a couple sentences or
但你可以写一两句话
bullet points on how the information in the article could relate to our problem
或者一些关于文章中有关我们问题的要点